Finding Aid for Thunder Bay Boom Company (Alpena, Mich.) Records, 1868-1912
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Thunder Bay Boom Company (Alpena, Mich.) Records 1868-1912
Thunder Bay Boom Company (Alpena, Mich.)
3 linear ft. and 6 oversize volumes
85595 Bb.2/2; BB.2
Alpena, Michigan lumber company; minutes of stockholders' meetings, financial records, and time books.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The bulk of the records came from Philip Kingsbury Fletcher (donor no. 17 ) in 1953; other records came from Mrs. Ralph Fletcher (donor no. 4672 ) in 1968.
The record group is open to research.
The Thunder Bay River Boom Company was formed in 1868 by a group of investors eager to exploit the timber riches surrounding the area of Alpena, Michigan. Its purpose was to control the logging and millwork that was done on the Thunder Bay River, and to separate the logs of the various companies. In 1898, the company was re-established as the Thunder Bay Boom Company. In 1911, the assets of the company were sold.
The record group consists of financial records, time books of company employees, and articles of incorporation and minutes of stockholders.
The researcher should also consult the papers of the Fletcher Family which contains business correspondence relating to their involvement in the company.
Subjects:
Alpena (Mich.); Business records.; Labor--Michigan--Alpena.; Logging--Michigan--Alpena.; Log driving--Michigan--Thunder Bay River.
- Ledgers
  - March 1868-January 1875 (Box 1)
  - June 1875-December 1876 (Box 1)
  - January 1877-March 1879 (Box 1)
  - March 1879-February 1881 (Box 1)
  - March 1881-January 1883 (Volume 1)
  - January 1894-April 1898 (Volume 2)
  - April 1898-June 1901 (Box 1)
  - June 1901-April 1910 (Box 1)
  - April 1910-January 1912 (Box 1)
- Journals
  - May 1875-December 1878 (Box 2)
  - February 1881-January 1885 (Box 2)
  - April 1885-December 1892 (Box 2)
  - 1894-1898 (Volume 3)
  - April 1898-June 1901 (Box 2)
  - June 1901-December 1906 (Box 2)
  - January 1907-January 1912 (Box 2)
- Time Books
  - 1872 (Box 3)
  - March 1874-December 1877 (Box 3)
  - January 1878-June 1880 (Box 3)
  - July 1880-April 1883 (Box 3)
  - 1883-1885 (Volume 4)
  - April 1910-November 1911 (Box 3)
- Other records
  - Articles of incorporation and minutes, 1898-1899 (Box 3)
  - Stockholders minute book, 1868-1893 (Box 3)
  - Stockholders minute book, 1898-1911 (Box 3)
  - Laborers ledger, 1882 (Box 3)
  - Cash book, May 1875-October 1878 (Box 3)
  - Cash Book, November 1878-February 1881 (Box 3)
  - Cash Book, June 1905-December 1911 (Box 3)
  - State Tax Land Deeds (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1871-1897 (Box 3)
  - Scaler's daily reports of logs cut, 1906-1907 (Volume 5)
  - Scaler's daily reports of logs cut, 1908-1909 (Volume 6)